Alexander Mills

Senior Software Engineer + DevOps San Francisco, CA 415-730-1805 / alexander.d.mills@gmail.com

Important Links / URLs

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexanderdmills</u>

StackOverflow (65k+ points !!) https://stackoverflow.com/users/1223975/alexander-mills

<u>unix.stackexchange.com</u> (7k+ points) <u>https://unix.stackexchange.com/users/113238/alexander-mills</u>

Github (200+ repos) https://www.github.com/oresoftware

Summary

Well-rounded and outgoing software developer with 9+ years experience in engineering and product design. Experienced in both B2B and B2C industries, and with government contracting. *Expert with Node.js, TypeScript, Golang and all things Docker.* Looking for interesting work *only in the San Francisco area (but open to remote work)*. Prefer back-end software roles, including devops, SRE, data engineering, release engineering, platform engineering, etc.

Very experienced with AWS and GCP, and to a lesser extent Azure. Generally speaking I am most excited by companies that are oriented towards hardware, tangible goods, IoT, quantitative/financial, video/audio platforms, mobile-first. My primary skills involve creating full-stack apps with JavaScript and Node.js, Java, shell-scripting, Docker, relational and non-relational databases, operations research, system architecture, and some data science. My goal is to work in software development and engineering – and although an eventual move into management may be inevitable, I'd like to always be doing some engineering work. Expert in testing software, and experienced with CI/CD and deploying software on multiple platforms.

I am motivated by interesting projects that do good in the world. Top 1% on StackOverflow since 2015. Very active on Github and have written and published a ton of OSS, developing many libraries and SDKs. Certified to work on both AWS and GCP platforms (see certifications section below). I view software as a means to achieve engineering feats, but academically I am interested in functional languages, and strive to write clean code, following functional programming best practices.

Technical / Software Skills

Software Languages and Libraries

Backend: Node.js / TypeScript, Golang, Java, Bash/Shell
Frontend (Web): JS, React, Angular, RxJS, ReasonML

Currently learning: Erlang / Elixir, OCaml, Rust, Scala

Software Testing JUnit, Mocha, Karma, Selenium

Deployment, monitoring, continuous integration, AWS (EKS, ECS, EC2, S3, RDS, etc), GCP, Docker, Jenkins, TravisCI, OpenShift /

hosting, PaaS / SaaS OpenStack, CircleCI, Heroku, various CDNs including JFrog / Artifactory, Kubernetes

Databases, Datastores

Relational: Oracle RDBMS (PL/SQL), MySQL / MariaDB, SQLite, Postgres
Non-relational: MongoDB, DB4O (an object database), Redis

Work Experience

Interos Solutions, Inc.

San Francisco, CA

Devops and Platform Engineer

March 2019 - Present

- Devops for start-up firm based out of Northern Virginia, with an arm in Silicon Valley.
- Worked with AWS to deploy our software, using AWS services including EC2, EKS and ECS to deploy containerized applications.
- Deployed, monitored, audited our software for security, best practices, compliance with federal law, etc.
- Managed CI/CD pipelines for our software deployment process using standard tools like Jenkins, and code repositories including Bitbucket, Github and content delivery services like AWS S3.
- Conducted application development for several Node is and Python codebases and wrote tooling with TypeScript, Python, Bash for all sorts of things, including jenkins jobs, front-end apps, and full-fledged microservices for internal use.

San Francisco, CA Moover

Devops, Software Developer (Co-founder and CTO)

May 2016 - Dec. 2018

Aug. 2016 - Nov. 2016

- Worked in capacity of CTO and full-stack dev working with Node.js and front-end JS.
- Modernizing the moving ("mooving") industry! Writing/testing/deploying full-stack JS applications via AWS.
- Consumer-facing web + mobile application to provide real-time and on-demand moving ("mooving") services; involved both B2B and B2C aspects (where the B2B side required working with local moving companies.
- Managed deployment on Elastic Beanstalk, as well as deployment to Firebase. Front-end development was done with React.
- Worked part-time and full-time after I left Cisco; worked in the capacity of CTO after previous CTO left.

Cisco San Francisco, CA Feb. 2017 - June 2018

Lead Developer, Devops

- Lead developer on full-stack JS project (MEAN stack), managing our CI/CD pipelines, doing all the devops work, both front-end and back-end testing, and acting as the project DBA as well.
- The project involved web applications targeting internal and external Cisco customers in order to improve the acquisition process (working as part of the M&A team at Cisco).
- Applications involved real-time features requiring advanced knowledge of websockets and MongoDB, which I had gained on previous jobs.
- Migrated our apps from Angular 1.0 to Angular 2.0 before I left, upgrading everything to TypeScript in the process.
- Lead our team in moving from OpenShift version 2 to version 3; effectively moving from VMs to containers.

Autodesk San Rafael, CA

Software Developer (3-month contract)

Short-term contract to develop low-latency RESTful APIs with Node.js using the StrongLoop / Loopback

- Used Loopback framework to develop a data-first methodology to develop APIs (postgres tables drove the codebase; the codebase did not generate the tables).
- Incorporated the built-in data-access / access-control features of Loopback.

Lectal Palo Alto, CA

Software Developer (Co-founder)

Lectal was a small early-stage startup, making consumer web applications.

- Writing/testing/deploying full-stack JS applications deployed via Heroku and later AWS; (MEAN stack).
- Customer-facing social-networking news app with sophisticated AI components designed to optimize news experience for everyone!
- Created several open-source Node.js modules for scaling servers to fit our needs.
- Created custom service to tail the MongoDB oplog to provide scale-able solution to update Algolia search indexes.
- 3rd party integrations with Cloudinary, Algolia, Facebook, Twitter, etc.

Comcast Sunnyvale, CA

Software Developer

Worked at Comcast's Silicon Valley research arm. (Formerly Comcast Labs, now called Comcast Silicon Valley Innovation Center).

- Used full-stack JavaScript to create internet of things (IoT) solutions; using big data to close the customer service
- Wrote and deployed Node is rules-engine services which handled up to 250 requests per second for all Comcast business across the USA; used Redis for caching data.
- Created full-stack universal / isomorphic JavaScript management and admin web applications using React.is.
- Mentored and pair-programmed with junior developers; left Comcast to work at Lectal full-time.

TASC Washington, DC June 2010 - Jan. 2014

Java and Oracle Developer

As a junior to mid-level developer on a multi-million dollar project, I developed and deployed a major Java-based software project to hundreds of government customers.

- Coded more than 80% of the time on a day-to-day basis, and 60% of that time in Java, 40% with Oracle PL/SQL.
- Developed, maintained, debugged, and optimized Java and Oracle PL/SQL, using the Eclipse IDE and Oracle SQL Developer. Wrote unit tests using JUnit for the majority of the Java classes I wrote.

The Research Foundation of the State **University of New York**

Buffalo, NY Aug 2008 - Nov. 2010

Aug. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Apr. 2015 - Apr. 2016

Researcher / Author

Lead author of conference (GITMA, Mexico City, 2009) paper and published journal (JIPS) paper on disaster mitigation. (See: Publications, below.) This paper has 70K citations.

Formal Education

University at Buffalo, SUNY

May 2010

Certifications / License

- Google Certified Associate Cloud Engineer (expected 2021)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (expected 2021)
- USSF D/E Soccer Coaching license

Open Source Software

- https://www.npmjs.com/~oresoftware
- https://github.com/oresoftware

Publications

- "The World Might be Missing a Programming Language" (url: https://medium.com/better-programming/the-world-might-be-missing-a-programming-language-4ce43e212277)
- "Web 2.0 Emergency Applications: How Useful Can Twitter Be in Emergency Response?" (Journal of Information Privacy and Security, Volume 5, Issue 3, 2009)
- "Hot-reloading in 2017, using React + RequireJS (and Node.js, of course)" (url: https://medium.com/@the1mills/hot-reloading-with-react-requirejs-7b2aa6cb06e1)
- "Front-end JavaScript testing with Istanbul and Selenium" (url: https://medium.com/@the1mills/front-end-javascript-test-coverage-with-istanbul-selenium-4b2be44e3e98)
- "How to test your new NPM module without publishing it every 5 minutes" (url: https://bit.lv/2CNORf0)